Inventory of the Stone-Moore Papers, 1860-1957
Earl Gregg Swem Library, College of William and Mary
Special Collections, Earl Gregg Swem Library, College of William and Mary
Stone-Moore Papers 1860-1957
Special Collections, Earl Gregg Swem Library, College of William and Mary
2010.085
1.49 Cubic Feet
Stone, Edward L. (Edward Lee) (1864-1938); Moore, L. Franklin
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
Collection is open to all researchers.
Acquisition Information
This collection was purchased in January 2010.
Biographical Information
Edward Lee Stone (1864-1938) was born September 15, 1864, in Liberty, Virginia (now known as Bedford, VA) and died in 1938. After working for John P. Bell's printing company, Stone was promoted and eventually took over the business. He became a wealthy and prominent citizen of Roanoke through his business, the Stone Printing and Manufacturing Company. He also played an important role in his local community through various civic organizations and clubs. Stone became ill in 1935 and gave control of his business to his son-in-law, L. Franklin Moore. His wife was Minnie Fishburn and his daughter Mary Katherine Stone.
Scope and Content
Personal papers, correspondence and business records of Edward L. Stone (1869-1938) and his son-in-law, Franklin Moore of Roanoke, Virginia. Both men owned the Roanoke Printing and Manufacturing Company and were involved in various civic organizations.
Arrangement
This collection is organized into five series: Series 1: Correspondence and Personal Papers, Series 2: Photographs, Series 3: Business and Financial Documents, Series 4: Political Tracts and Series 5: Ephemera.
Index Terms
Subjects:
Printing--Virginia--History; Roanoke (Va.)--History; Stone Printing and Manufacturing Company (Roanoke, Va.)
Genre and Form Terms:
Business records; Correspondence; Photographs
Detailed Description of the Collection
- Series 1: Correspondence and Personal Papers 1880-1952
  This series holds correspondence for Edward Stone and Franklin Moore and personal papers for each are also included. The series is primarily organized into general correspondence for each individual.
  - Stone Correspondence 1880-1899 (Box-folder 1:1)
  - Stone Correspondence 1920-1925 (Box-folder 1:2)
  - Stone-Hunter Correspondence 1931 (Box-folder 1:3)
  - Stone-Hoffer Correspondence 1932-1934 (Box-folder 1:4)
  - Stone Correspondence undated (Box-folder 1:5)
  - Stone Greeting Cards, Invitations, and Unsigned Notes undated (Box-folder 1:6)
  - Moore Correspondence 1938-1939 (Box-folder 1:7)
  - Moore Correspondence 1940-1945 (Box-folder 1:8)
  - Moore Correspondence 1946-1953 (Box-folder 1:9)
  - Moore-Everett WaddetCorrespondence 1939 (Box-folder 1:10)
  - Moore-Noland Correspondence 1944-1952 (Box-folder 1:11)
  - Moore Correspondence undated (Box-folder 2:1)
  - Moore Greeting Cards, Invitations, and Unsigned Notes undated (Box-folder 2:2)
  - Moore Greeting Cards, Invitations, and Unsigned Notes undated (Box-folder 2:3)
  - Grandfather Moore Correspondence 1951 (Box-folder 2:4)
- Series 2: Photographs circa 1940s
  This series is composed of photographs of the Moore family, including some taken on a fishing trip.
  - Fishing Trip Photographs circa 1940s (Box-folder 2:5)
  - Moore Family Photographs circa 1940s (Box-folder 2:6)
- Series 3: Business and Financial Documents 1860-1957
  This series contains the business and financial records of Edward Stone and Franklin Moore. It includes records for local businesses, clubs, and charities' stockholders reports.
  - Stone Financial Records 1860-1924 (Box-folder 2:7)
  - Roanoke Community Fund 1925-1939 (Box-folder 2:8)
  - Roanoke Community Fund 1939-1950 (Box-folder 2:9)
  - Roanoke Hospital 1931-1939 (Box-folder 3:1)
  - Virginia Manufacturers Association 1936-1945 (Box-folder 3:2)
  - Virginia Manufacturers Association 1940 (Box-folder 3:3)
  - Financial Records for Virginia Railroads 1939-1952 (Box-folder 3:4)
  - YMCA Roanoke 1945 (Box-folder 3:5)
  - Rotary Club of Roanoke 1945-1949 (Box-folder 3:6)
  - Charity Solicitations 1945-1952 (Box-folder 3:6)
  - Shenandoah Club 1946 (Box-folder 3:8)
  - Princess Anne Club 1948-1949 (Box-folder 3:9)
  - Virginia Military Institute 1950-1951 (Box-folder 3:10)
  - Stockholders Reports 1935-1948 (Box-folder 3:11)
  - Stockholders Reports 1949-1957 (Box-folder 4:1)
- Series 4: Political Tracts 1935-1950
  This series includes political tracts regarding inflation in the 1930s and relevant correspondence with Edward Stone and Franklin Moore. Some of the texts also address general economic issues in the United States and the sporting group, the Izaak Walton Club.
  - Political Tracts and Correspondence Regarding Inflation 1935-1936 (Box-folder 4:2)
  - Political and Economic Tracts 1940-1950 (Box-folder 4:3)
- Series 5: Ephemera 1882-1956
  This series contains collected ephemera from the period such as newspapers, magazines, and prints from Stone Printing Company.
  - Printed Materials 1882-1949 (Box-folder 4:4)
  - Printed Materials 1950-1956 (Box-folder 4:5)
  - Mass Mail Ephemera 1940s-1950s (Box-folder 4:6)
  - Printing Trade Ephemera circa 1930s-1940s (Box-folder 5:1)
  - Stone Company Prints undated (Box-folder 5:2)
  - Newspapers 1933-1950 (Box-folder 5:3)
  - YWCA Roanoke Pamphlets 1949 (Box-folder 5:4)